<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article [
<!ENTITY version "1.0.53">
<!ENTITY mdash  "--">
<!ENTITY hellip "...">
<!ENTITY copy       "&#x00A9;"> <!-- COPYRIGHT SIGN -->
        <!-- replace version above with actual application version number-->
	<!--  Template Version: 1.0.1  (do not remove this line) -->



<!ENTITY APPLET-TEMPLATE-1x-SHELL SYSTEM
"templates/applet_template_1-applet.sgml.cdata">
<!ENTITY APPLET-TEMPLATE-1x SYSTEM
"templates/applet_template_1.sgml.cdata">
]>

<!--  Version: 1.0.1  -->

<article id="index">
  <articleinfo>

    <authorgroup>

      <author>
        <firstname>David</firstname>
        <surname>Mason</surname>
        <affiliation>
          <orgname>Red Hat, Inc.</orgname>
          <address>
            <email>dcm@redhat.com</email>
          </address>
        </affiliation>
      </author>

      <author>
        <firstname>Daniel</firstname>
        <surname>Mueth</surname>
        <affiliation>
          <address>
            <email>d-mueth@uchicago.edu</email>
        >
    
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>
          0.99
        </revnumber>
        <date>
         04.10.2, Daniel Mueth, and Alexander Kirillov</holder>
    </copyright>

    <legalnotice>
     <para>
      Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
      document under the terms of the <citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
      License</citetitle>, Version 1.1 or any later version published
      by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant Sections, no
      Fronoject ####### -->

    <sect2 id="gdp">
      <title>The GNOME Documentation Project</title>

      <sect3 id="goals">
        <title>Goals</title>
        <para>
          The GNOME Documentation Project (GDP) aims to provide GNOME
          and GNOME applications with a complete, intuitive, and clear
          documentation system.  At the center of the GDP is the
          <appl as well as other Linux documentation such as man pages and
          texinfo documents. The GNOME Help System provides a
          comprehensive view of documentation on a machine by
          dynamically assembling the documentation of GNOME
          applications and components which are installed. The GDP is
          responsible for writing numerous GNOME-related documents,
  >
       This Handbook is a guide for both writing documentation for
       GNOME components and applications and for properly binding and
       packaging documentation into GNOME applications.
      </para>
      <para>
       This Handbook, like all GNOIt is also important to spend some time with GNOME to make
          sure you are familiar enough with it to be
          <emphasis>authoritative</emphasis>  in your writing. The
          best way to do this is to just sit down and play with GNOME
       e encourage everybody to use this DTD instead of the
          default DocBook DTD since your source document header and
       pport
          by hand:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist mark="opencircle">
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Download <ulink
              url="http://www.labs.redhat.com/png/png-support.html">the
              GDP DocBook DTD fo
              of your SGML CATALOG file may vary depending upon your
              distribution. (On Red Hat it is usually in
              /usr/lib/sgml/CATALOG.) Add the following line to this
              file:
              <programlisting>
PUBLIC "-//GNOME//DTD DocBook PNG Variant V1.0//EN" "png-support-3.0.dtd"
              </programlisting> 
              If you are using the 3.1 DTD, use:
              <programlisting>
PUBLIC "-//GNOME//DTD DocBook PNG Variant V1.1//EN" "png-support-3.1.dtd"
              </programlisting> 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
          Alternately, you can download and install the
          <ulink url="http://people.redhat.com/dcm/software.html"
          type="http">gn
          To include PNG files in your documents, you will need to
          indicate that you are using this special DTD.  To </programlisting>
        <para>
          You will notice in this example that the file
          <filename>myfile.png</filenamate an html file, it will
          automatically look for <filename>myfile.png</filename> in
          the directory.
        </para>
        <para>
          If you want to create PostScript ouput, you will need to create an
          EPS version of your image file to be displayed in the
          PostScript file. There is a simple script available which
          allows you to change a PNG image into an EPS file
          easily. You can download this file - img2eps - from <ulink
          url="http://people.redhat.com/dcm/sgml.html"
          type="html">http://people.redhat.com/dcm/sgml.html</ulink>
          (look for the img2 Note that it also
              describes some custom extensions of DocBook;
              fortunately, they are clearly marked<listitem>
            <para>
              <xref linkend="docbookbasics" /> - Descriptions of
              commonly used DocBook tags.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
          You may also discuss specifilly kept
        completely up-to-date with CVS and has a basic description of
        each file from CVS.
      </para>
    </sect2>

<!-- ####### Getting Started | Screenshots ####### -->

    <sect2 id="screenshots">
      <title>Screenshots</title>
      <para>
        Most GNOME documents will have screenshots of the particular
        applet, application, GNOME component, or widget being
        discussed.  As discussed above in <xref linkend="gdpdtd"/> you
        will need to install the special GDP DocBook DTD which
        supports PNG images, the format used for all images in GNOME
        documentation. For the basic DocBook structure used to insert
        images in a document, see <xref linkend="jadeimages"/> above.
      </para>
      <sect3 id="screenshotappearance">
        <title>Screenshot Appearance</title>
        <para>
          For all screenshots of windows that typically have border
          decorations (e.g. applications and dialogs, but not applets
          in a <interface>panel<to provide
          screenshots in this form, you should create screenshots as
          you wish them to appear and send them this way. If you
     don't have a three-button mouse, just 
     right-click on the applet and choose
     <guimenuitem>Move</guimenuitem>. The cursor will turn into a
     cross and the applet will move with your mouse until you press
     any mouse button to indicate you are finished moving it.
     If, in the course of this movement, it hits
     other objects, the behavior depends on the global preferences
     you have set for your <interface>Panels</interface> in the
     <application>GNOME Control Center</application>: the applet you are
     moving can switch places with other objects, "push" all objects
     it meets, or "jump" over all other objects without disturbing
     them. You can also override the default behavior by holding
     <keycap>Shct2>
  </sect1>


  <!-- #### Intro | The Right-Click Pop-Up Menu ###### -->
  <sect1 id="right-click-pop-up-menu">
   <title>The Right-Click Pop-Up Menu</title>
   <para>
    Clicking the right mouse button on any applet brings up
    a <guimenu>pop-up menu</guimenu>. This 
    menu always has certain standard menu items in it and
    often has additional items which vary depending on the particular
    applet. 
   </para>
   <sect2 id="standard-right-click-items"> 
    <title>Standard Pop-Up Items</title>         arrows in each direction). As you move your mouse, the applet
         will move with it.  When you have finished moving the applet,
         click any mouse button and the applet will anchor in its
         current position.  Note that applets ca> dialog.  This is helpful if
        you would like to test the effects of the changes you have
        made but may want to continue changing the properties.
       </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>
        <guibutton>Close</guibutton> &mdash;
        Pressing <guibutton>Close</guibutton> will close the
        <interface>Properties</interface> dialog.  Only changes in the
        configuration which were previously applied with the
        <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> button will p>
    <para>
     Many applets also have one or more of the following items in their
     right-click pop-up menu:
     <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
       <term>Run...</term>
       <listitem>
        <para>
         The <guimenuitem>Run...</guimen own window rather than in the
         panel. For example: 
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
         <listitem>
         d...</guimenuitem> menu item which
           starts the GNOME <application>CD Player</application> when
           selected, wh  </varlistentry>
     </variablelist>
    </para>
   </sect2>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="feedback">
   <title>Feedback</title>
   <sect2 id="reporting-bugs"> 
    <title>Reporting Applet Bugs</title>
    <para>
     GNOME users are encouraged to report bugs to <ulink type="http"
     url="http://bugs.gnome.org">The GNOME Bug Tracking
     System</ulink>.  The easiest way to submit bugs is to use the
     <application>Bug Report Tool</application> program by selecting
     <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>Main Mure to be complete in describing what you did to cause the
     bug to surface and, if possible, describe how the developer can
     reproduce the the scenario.
    </para>
   </sect2>
   <sect2 id="documentation-feedback"> 
    <title>Providing Feedback</        Context sensitive help is still in development.
      </para>
    </sect1>

####### Document Templates | Templates 5: Co</title>
      <programlisting>
<![CDATA[(Put sgml here.)]]>
      </programlisting>  
    </sect1>

####### Document Templates [CDATA[(Put sgml here.)]]>
      </programlisting>  
    </sect1>-->
  </appendix>

</article>
